Guide to the Park Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- APPENDIX A: INDEX TO SELECTED CORRESPONDENCE
  - Smith, Samuel Stanhope (1750-1819). ALS to the Rev. Dr. Green or Dr. Maclean. Dumfries, Va., November 19, 1802
  - Society for Propagating the Gospel. Note from Abiel Holmes, secretary, to Samuel Farrar informing him that he has been elected a member of the Society. Cambridge, Mass., November 9, 1881 (Box 3)
  - Somerset, Edward Adolphus Seymour, 11th duke of (1775-1855). ALS to an unnamed person. Devon, Eng., September 10, 1806
  - Spalding, Thomas. ALS to Bela Bates Edwards. Drury Lane, London, April 20, 1847 (Box 7)
  - Sprague, William Buell (1795-1876).
    - ALS to Bela Bates Edwards. Albany, N.Y., February 1, 1848
    - ALS to Edwards A. Park. Albany, N.Y., December 20, 1852 (Box 7)
  - Sprengel, Kurt (1766-1833). ALS in German to an unnamed person. Halle, Germany, February 28, 1792
  - Spring, Gardiner (1785-1873). ALS to Dr. Potts. New York, March 21, 1861
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.72
  - Spring, Samuel (1746-1819). 2 ALS to Eliphalet Pearson. Newburyport, Mass.:
    - October 15, 1809 (Box 3)
    - September 4, [1815] (Box 4)
  - Spurgeon, Charles Haddon (1834-1892). 2 ALS to Edwards A. Park. Clapham and Newington, Eng., August 12, 1878; October 6, 187? (Box 7)
  - Stanhope, Charles, 3rd earl (1753-1816). ALS to an unnamed person. Chevening House [Kent], August 23, 1805
    See: box 9, folder 119, v.3, p.66
  - Stanley, Arthur Penrhyn (1815-1881). ALS to William Edwards Park. Westminister, Eng., June 9, 1873 (Box 7)
  - Stansfeld, Sir James (1820-1898). ALS to an unnamed person. St. Leonards, Eng., October 30, 1863 (Box 7)
  - Staffer, Philip Albert (1766-1840). ALS in French to Frédéric Monod. Cahmplan, France, November 3, 1824
    See: box 10, folder 121, v.5, p.26
  - Stark, John (1728-1822). Certificate to a muster roll part of which is on verso. Albany [N.Y.], October 21, 1778
  - Starr, Samuel. ALS to Tapping Reeve. Troy, N.Y., August 26, 1809 (Box 3)
  - Stehensohn, Peter ?. ALS to Edwards A. Park. Salem, Mass., May 31, 1816?
    See: box 10, folder 121, v.5, p.59
  - Steuben, Friedrich Wilhelm Ludolph Gerhard Augustin, Baron von (1730-1794). LS to John Sullivan. West Point [N.Y.], Jul, 1783
    See: box 10, folder 122, v.6, p.16
  - Stewart, Dugald (1753-1828). Certification to the attendance of Alexander Murray in a moral philosophy class at Edinburgh University. Edinburgh, April 4, 1797
    See: box 9, folder 119, v.3, p.5
  - Stowe, Calvin Ellis (1802-1886).
    - ALS to the Rev. Edwards A. Park. Brunswick, Me., November 25, 1851
    - ALS to J. L. Taylor. Brooklyn, N.Y., April 11, 1855 (Box 7)
  - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth (Beecher) (1811-1896). Autograph copy of a Biblical quotation from Isaiah 40:4; signed. Andover, Mass., January 4, 1853
    See: box 9, folder 117, v.1, p.63
  - Strong, Hezekiah Wright (1768-1848). Passage from scripture with a question addressed to Edwards A. Park. [Amherst, Mass., Circa 1835] (Box 6)
  - Strond, William, M.D. Letter in the third person to the editors of the Bibliotheca Sacra. London, June 8, 1853
    See: box 9, folder 119, v.3, p.27
  - Stuart, Moses (1780-1852).
    - ALS to the Junior Class of Andover Theological Seminary. Andover, Mass., Monday, December 13, [1847] (Box 7)
    - ALS to Bela Bates Edwards. Andover, Mass., Sunday [no year] (Box 8)
    - ALS to Samuel Farrar. Andover, Mass., January 26, 1848 (Box 7)
    - 8 ALS to Eliphalet Pearson. New Haven:
      - July 18, 1808 (Box 3)
      - September 16, 1809 (Box 3)
      - November 25, 1809 (Box 3)
      - December 29, 1809 (Box 3)
      - January 19, 1810 (Box 3)
      - December 12, 1813 (Box 4)
        Fragment
      - [September 7, 1815] (Box 4)
      - Sunday [no year] (Box 8)
    - ALS to the Trustees of Phillips Academy. Andover, Mass., September 22, 1812 (Box 3)
    - ALS to Benjamin Silliman (1779-1864). Danbury, Conn., September 11, 1803 (Box 2)
  - Sullivan, John (1740-1795). ALS to Gen. James Clinton. Wyoming [Pa.], July 11, 1779
    See: box 10, folder 122, v.6, p.28
  - Sullivan, William (1774-1839). ALS to the Rev. Jonathan Burr. Boston, April 13, 1812
    See: box 9, folder 117, v.1, p.21
  - Sumner, George. ALS to Bela Bates Edwards. Paris, Saturday [1846] (Box 7)
  - Sumner, John Bird, bp. of Chester (1780-1862). ALS to J. Pellatt. Wandsworth [Surrey], May 16, 1829
  - Sutherland, George. Memorandum concerning his "Christian Psychology," sent probably to Edwards A. Park., [no place, undated] (Box 8)
  - Tappan, Arthur (1786-1865). ALS to Samuel Farrar. New York, August 29, 1833 (Box 6)
  - Tappan, Delia (Emmons) (1814-). ALS (signed Delia) to Nathanael Emmons. Hallowell, Me., March 25, 1830 (Box 6)
  - Tappan, Hannah (Pomeroy) Edwards (1795-1867). ALS to Samuel Farrar. Northampton, Mass., [ca. 1823] (Box 5)
  - Tappan, John (1781-). "Conditions of the deed of pews in Christ's Church [Boston]" with notes on the status of tenure in this and other Boston churches. Boston, [undated] (Box 8)
  - Taylor, Nathaniel William (1786-1858). ALS to Edwards A. Park. New Haven, November 29, 1851
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.51
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace (1811-1863). ALS to an unnamed person., [no place, circa 1850] (Box 7)
  - Thiersch, H. 2 ALS to Edwards A. Park. Marburgh, Germany, March 5, 1864; July 21, 1864 (Box 7)
  - Tholuck, Friedrich August Cottreu (1799-1877).
    - ALS to Bela Bates Edwards. [no place, 1846] (Box 7)
    - 3 LS to Edwards A. Park in German. Halle, Germany, May 27, 1866; August 11, 1866; November 11, 1873 (Box 7)
    - ALS to Edward Bouverie Pusey, introducing Edwards A. Park. Halle, Germany, June 7, 1843
  - Thomson, William McClure (1806-1894). ALS to W. F. Draper. Beirut, Syria, March 28, 1876 (Box 7)
  - Thorburn, G. & Son. Bill to Jessie [i.e. Jesse] Buel with note added by Grant Thorburn. New York, January 15, 1828 (Box 6)
  - Tiffany, Charles Comfort (1829-1907). ALS to Agnes Park. New York, January 18 [1899] (Box 8)
  - Tocqueville, Alexis Charles Henri Clérel de (1805-1859). ALS in French to an unnamed person. Paris, February 18, 1850
    See: box 10, folder 121, v.5, p.34
  - Torrey, John (1796-1873). ALS to an unnamed person. Princeton, N.J., June 30, 1851 (Box 7)
  - Treadwell, James Wetmore. ALS to Ann Maria (Edwards) Park. New York, February 14, 1879 (Box 7)
  - Treadwell, John (1745-1823). ALS to Nathanael Emmons. Farmington, Conn., August 25, 1796 (Box 2)
  - Treadwell, Rosin (Hamill). ALS to Ann Maria (Edwards) Park. Flushing, N.Y., January 24, 1879 (Box 7)
  - Tuckerman, Joseph (1778-1840). Copy of a letter to John Adams (1772-1863). Chelsea, Mass., August 5, 1818 (Box 5)
  - Twichell, Joseph Hopkins (1838-1918). ALS to an unnamed person. Hartford, Conn., June 1, 1872 (Box 7)
  - Tyler, Bennet (1783-1858). Certification to the Moderator of the Hamden Association of the membership of Noah Bishop in the Church Theological Institute of Conn. East Windsor, Conn., February 9, 1838
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.47
  - Tyler, John, pres. U.S. (1790-1862). ALS to Mr. Tasistro. Sherwood Forest, Charles City Co., Va., January 11, 1847
    See: box 10, folder 122, v.6, p.50
  - Tyng, Stephen Higginson (1800-1885). ALS to an unnamed person. New York, January 11, 1871 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified.
    - ALS (name not deciphered) to Henry Allon. Crystal Palace, London, June 4 [no year] (Box 8)
    - AL (signed with initials P, B or R; E) to Sarah (Burr) Reeve. Boston, August 13 [no year] (Box 8)
    - Geographical exercise, written in French, probably by a schoolchild. Alexandre, October 5, 1788
  - U.S. Dept. of State. LS from Hamilton Fish, sec., to Blacquebey, Turkish ambassador to the U.S. Washington, January 10, 1873 (Box 7)
  - U.S. President (1861-1865) (Lincoln). Appointment, signed by Abraham Lincoln, President, and Edwin M. Stanton, Secretary of War, of Henry Edwards as Allotment Commissioner of Mass. soldiers in U.S. Army. Washington, February 25, 1862 (Box 7)
  - U.S. Secretary of War. Letter to Edwards A. Park, signed by W. C. Endicott, Secretary of War. Washington, July 12, 1887 (Box 7)
  - U.S. War Dept.
    - Letter signed by John C. Calhoun to William Durkee Williamson. Washington, May 2, 1822
    - Letter signed by Henry Knox, sec., to the Governor of Mass. Washington, August 16, 1793
  - Updike, Wilkins (1784-1867). "Minutes respecting Dr. Samuel Hopkins which I took from Stephen Cahoone...in 1850." A physical description of Hopkins.
  - Van Buren, Martin, pres. U.S. (1782-1862). ALS to Mr. Clouck? Washington, December 11, 1830
    See: box 10, folder 122, v.6, p.46
  - Vater, Johann Severin (1771-1826). ALS to Dr. Eberhard. Königsberg, Germany, September 27, 1822
    See: box 10, folder 121, v.5, p.60
  - Verne, Jules (1828-1905). ALS in French to Olin A. Brainerd. Amiens, France, November 8, 1879 (Box 7)
  - Vinet, Alexandre (1797-1847). ALS to Frédéric Monod. [no place], June 5, 1846 (Box 7)
  - Voss, Christian Daniel (1761-1821). Announcement in German of postponement of a lecture. Halle, Germany, [undated]
    See: box 10, folder 121, v.5, p.30
  - Wadsworth, Benjamin (1693-1737). Certification to Joseph Prout, town clerk of Boston, of marriages performed by the writer. Boston, October 21, 1717
  - Waldo, Daniel (1762-1864). ALS to A. Pearson concerning her father, Eliphalet Pearson. Washington, June 20, 1856 (Box 7)
  - Wardlaw, Ralph (1779-1853). ALS to an unnamed person. Golden Cross, Thursday, February 22 [no year]
    See: box 9, folder 119, v.3, p.52
  - Ware, Henry (1764-1845). [missing text] Henry Ware and William Dandridge Peck into professorships at Harvard University. Cambridge, Mass., May 14, 1805 (Box 2)
  - Ware, Nathaniel (1697-1781). Ledger of Nathaniel Ware, farmer, of Wrentham, Mass., 1727-1767 (Box 1)
  - Ware, William (1797-1852). ALS to James Munroe, Sr. West Cambridge [Mass.], April 23, 1844
    See: box 9, folder 117, v.1, p.37
  - Warner, Charles Dudley (1829-1900). ALS to an unnamed person. Hartford, Conn., September 17, 1878 (Box 7)
  - Washington, George, pres. U.S. (1732-1799). LS to Col. Elias Dayton. New Windsor [N.Y.], April 11, 1781
    See: box 10, folder 122, v.6, p.32
  - Watson, Richard, bp of Landoff (1737-1816). Certification to the license of John Porter as curate in certain parish churches of Monmouth County., January 2, 1789
  - Watts, Alaric Alexander (1797-1864). ALS to an unnamed person. [no place], Tuesday [no year] (Box 8)
  - Waugh, Alexander (1754-1827). ALS to Thomas Burder. Marylebone, Eng., December 5, 1814
    See: box 10, folder 121, v.5, p.46
  - Wayland, Francis (1796-1865).
    - ALS to Henry Chapin. Brown University, December 11, 1848
    - ALS to Eliphalet Pearson. Andover, Mass., August 18, 1817 (Box 4)
  - Webster, Daniel (1782-1852).
    - ALS to Samuel Farrar. Boston, May 6, 1823 (Box 5)
    - ALS to the Rev. Edwards A. Park. Washington, June 29, 1850
  - Webster, Noah (1758-1843). AL (signed with initials) to an unnamed person., [no place, undated]
    See: box 9, folder 117, v.1, p.2
  - Weed, Thurlow (1797-1882). ALS to E. H. Blatchford. Albany, N.Y., March 9, 1847 (Box 7)
  - Weimar, Germany. Landes-Industrie-Comptoir. Letter in German to the Jaegersche Buchhandlung Frankfort. Weimar, Germany, March 25, 1803
  - Weir, Robert Walter (1803-1889). ALS to a publisher. West Point [N.Y.], August 7, 1849
  - Wellwood, Sir, Henry Moncrieff (1750-1827). ALS to Mrs. Pattison. Edinburgh, January 8, 1827
  - West, Maria A. ALS to Edwards A. Park. Smyrna, Asia Minor, February 13, 1878 (Box 7)
  - West, Stephen (1735-1819).
    - 2 ALS to Nathanael Emmons. Stockbridge, Mass., November 10, 1792; another about this date (Box 2)
    - 2 ALS to Jeremiah West. Stockbridge, Mass.:
      - September 15, 1797 (Box 2)
      - January 17, 1805 (Box 2)
  - Whately, Richard, abp of Dublin (1787-1863). Autograph.
  - Wheelock, Eleazar (1711-1779). ALS to Naphtali Daggett. Lebanon, N.H., February 5, 1770
  - Wheelock, John (1754-1817). ALS to Nathanael Emmons. Dartmouth College, August 25, 1798
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.31
  - Whelpley, Philip Melancthon (1792-1824). ALS to Samuel Fisher. New York, November 25, 1822
  - Whitaker, Nathaniel (1730-1795). ALS to Eleazar Wheelock. Salem, Mass., March 17, 1775
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.37
  - Whitefield, George (1714-1770). ALS to the [unintelligible] Mr. McCullock. London, January 12, 1743
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.17
  - Whittier, John Geenleaf (1807-1892). ALS to an unnamed person. Haverhill [Mass.], February 4, 1836
    See: box 9, folder 117, v.1, p.53
  - Wilberforce, William (1759-1833).
    - ALS to John Hatchard. Bath, Eng., April 28, 1826 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Joseph Lancaster. Bromfield, August 16, 1802
  - Wilks, Matthew. ALS to Thomas Wilson. Hoxton, August 3, 1816
    See: box 9, folder 119, v.3, p.21
  - Williams, Edward (1750-1813). Letter, unsigned, inquiring about materials to be used in a life of Jonathan Edwards. Rotherham [Yorks.], January 25, 1805
    See: box 9, folder 119, v.3, p.29
  - Williams, Thomas (1779-1876). ALS to Nathanael Emmons. Providence, R.I., August 5, 1833 (Box 6)
  - Winkler, Karl Gottlieb Theodore (1775-1856).
    - ALS in German to J. Sendtner. Dresden, Germany, September 13, 1819
    - Autograph note in German, signed, to an unnamed person. [no place], October 8, 1842 (Box 7)
  - Winthrop, Robert Charles (1809-1894). ALS to Edwards A. Park. Boston, March 23, 1882 (Box 7)
  - Witherspoon, Jonathan. ALS to Thomas Willing, June 7, 1787
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.34
  - Woodbury, Levi. ALS to David Henshaw, August 13, 1829
    See: box 9, folder 118, v.2, p.47
  - Woods, Leonard. ALS to Dr. Emmons, August 9, 1830
    See: box 10, folder 120, v.4, p.60
  - Woolsey, T.D. ALS to Bela Bates Edwards, July 3, 1844
  - Wright, Silas. ALS to Benjamin F. Butler, February 16, 1839
    See: box 9, folder 118, v.2, p.36
- APPENDIX B: SUPPLEMENTAL INDEX TO CORRESPONDENCE AND PAPERS (Not available online; consult Reference Archivist)